Mss.Ms.Coll.113
American Philosophical Society
- Series III. Works By Friedman, 1.5 linear feet
  - Ultraviolet Transmission of "Counting" Diamonds, 1948 (Box 9)
  - Undirected Research, 1973 (Box 9)
  - The Universe After Einstein, 1979 (Box 9)
  - Voltage Stablization by Means of the Corona Discharge Between Coaxial Cylinders, 1947 (Box 9)
  - Workshop on Non-Governmental International Engineering Organizations, 1988 (Box 9)
  - The World We Face In 1985, 1965 (Box 9)
  - X-Ray Astronomy Slides, Undated (Box 9)
  - X-Ray Background Radiation, Undated (Box 9)
  - X-Ray Fluoresence Analysis of Ethyl Fluid in Aviation Gasoline, 1950 (Box 9)
  - X-Rays From Exploding Stars and Galaxies, Undated (Box 9)
  - The X-ray K-Absorption Edges of the Elements Fe(26) to Ge(32), 1939 (Box 9)
  - The X-Rays KB2,5 - Emission Lines and K-Absorption Limits of Cu-Zn Alloys, 1940 (Box 9)
  - Yakov Borisovich Zel'Dovich, Biographical Note, 1990 (Box 9)
- Series IV. Naval Research Laboratory, 7.0 linear feet
  Series IV, the second largest in the collection, consists of correspondence, official reports and papers from Dr. Friedman’s career at the Navy Research Laboratory. The series includes work from scientists that Dr. Friedman worked with and supervised, including Dr. Talbot A. Chubb and Dr. George R. Carruthers. The correspondence is organized chronologically, as names are rarely used; internal code numbers are used instead. Dr. Friedman was, for some time, Code 7100, but used other designations as well. Signatures on memos and letters are best consulted to be sure of the author.
  - 75th Birthday Celebration, 1991 (Box 10)
  - Accident and Injury Information, 1968 (Box 10)
  - Assisant Secretary of the Navy Organization Memo, 1977 (Box 10)
  - An Interim Report of British Work on JOE, 1949 (Box 10)
  - Apollo/Soyuz, K-1590F, 1973-1976, undated (Box 10)
  - Apollo-Soyuz Proposal, 1973
  - Apollo Soyuz, X-Ray Experiment Preliminary Science Report, 1975 (Box 10)
  - Building 209 Dedication, 1968 (Box 10)
  - Buildings and Facilities Assignments, 1967-1978 (Box 10)
  - Clippings, 1967-1969 (Box 10)
  - Collection and Identification of Fission Products of Foreign Origin, 1949 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence, 1949-52, 1949-1952 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence, 1952-55, 1952-1955 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence, 1956 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence, 1957, Folder 1 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence, 1957, Folder 2 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence, 1957, Folder 3 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence, 1958, Folder 1 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence, 1958, Folder 2 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence, 1960-1971 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence, 1963-65, 1963-1965 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence, 1966-67, 1966-1967 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 11)
  - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence, 1980-81, 1980-1981 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence, 1987 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 12)
  - Correspondence, 1992, Folder 1 (Box 13)
  - Correspondence, 1992, Folder 2 (Box 13)
  - Correspondence, 1993, Folder 1 (Box 13)
  - Correspondence, 1993, Folder 2 (Box 13)
  - Correspondence, 1994, Folder 1 (Box 13)
  - Correspondence, 1994, Folder 2 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, 1995-96, Folder 1, 1995-1996 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, 1995-96, Folder 2, 1995-1996 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, 1997-99, 1997-1999 (Box 14)
  - Dailey, Carroll and Thomas A. Parnell, HEAO-A Observatory Description, 1977 (Box 14)
  - Dumand Materials, 1978 (Box 14)
  - EOHC, Annual Report to NASA, 1969 (Box 14)
  - EAHC Annual Report, 1976 (Box 14)
  - EOHC, Alan J. Grobecker Material, 1964-1970 (Box 15)
  - EOHC, Carl A. Rouse Materials, Folder 1, 1971-1975 (Box 15)
  - EOHC, Carl A. Rouse Materials, Folder 2, 1965-1970 (Box 15)
  - EOHC, Colloquia Advertisements, 1972-1978 (Box 15)
  - EOHC Correspondence, 1963 (Box 15)
  - EOHC Correspondence, A-B, 1963-1974 (Box 15)
  - EOHC Correspondence, C-D, 1963-1973 (Box 15)
  - EOHC Correspondence, E-F, 1963-1971 (Box 15)
  - EOHC Correspondence, G-H, 1963-1973 (Box 15)
  - EOHC Correspondence, I-J, Undated (Box 15)
  - EOHC Correspondence, K-L, 1969-1974 (Box 15)
  - EOHC Correspondence, M-N, 1963-1973 (Box 16)
  - EOHC Correspondence, O-P, 1963-1974 (Box 16)
  - EOHC Correspondence, Q-R, 1963-1969 (Box 16)
  - EOHC Correspondence, S-T, 1963-1973 (Box 16)
  - EOHC Correspondence, U-W, 1963-1974 (Box 16)
  - EOHC Correspondence, X-Z, 1963 (Box 16)
  - EOHC, Funding Proposal, 1970, 1969-1970 (Box 16)
  - EOHC, Job Inquiries, Undated (Box 16)
  - EOHC, Correspondence, Max Planck Institute, 1971 (Box 16)
  - EOHC, Post Doctoral Program, Adviser Nominations, 1972 (Box 16)
  - EOHC, Post Doctoral Program, Approved Research Proposals, 1972-1975 (Box 16)
  - EOHC, Post Doctoral Program, Correspondence, Undated (Box 16)
  - EOHC, Post Doctoral Program Materials, 1966-1979 (Box 16)
  - EOHC, Dianne K. Prinz, 1967-1971 (Box 16)
  - EOHC, Dror Sadeh Material, Folder 1, 1964-1969 (Box 16)
  - EOHC, Dror Sadeh Material, Folder 2, 1970-1979 (Box 16)
  - EOHC, George R. Carruthers Material, 1963-1976 (Box 17)
  - EOHC, George A. Doschek Material, 1968-1969 (Box 17)
  - EOHC, Guenter Brueckner Material, 1977-1978 (Box 17)
  - EOHC, Infrared Night Sky Experiment, 1964-1966 (Box 17)
  - EOHC, James D. Kurfess Material, 1968-1969 (Box 17)
  - EOHC, John H. Carver Material, 1967-1972 (Box 17)
  - EOHC, Martin Harwit Material, 1962-1968 (Box 17)
  - EOHC, N. P. Patterson Material, 1966-1967 (Box 17)
  - EOHC, Paul Feldman Material, 1965-1976 (Box 17)
  - EOHC, Proposal to NASA, 1966 (Box 17)
  - EOHC, Proposal to NASA, 1967 (Box 17)
  - EOHC, Proposal to NASA, 1968, 1967-1968 (Box 17)
  - EOHC, Proposal to NASA, 1969 (Box 17)
  - EOHC, Proposal to NASA, 1971 (Box 17)
  - EOHC, Proposal to NASA, 1973, 5.0 items (Box 18)
  - EOHC, Proposal to NASA, 1974, 5.0 items (Box 18)
  - EOHC, Proposal to NASA, 1975, 1974; 1.0 item (Box 18)
  - EOHC, Proposal to NASA, 1976, 1975; 2.0 items (Box 18)
  - EOHC, Proposal to NASA, 1977, 1976; 2.0 items (Box 18)
  - EOHC Publicity Literature, 1963-1964; undated; 44.0 items (Box 18)
  - EOHC, William Benesch Materials, 1963; 4.0 items (Box 18)
  - EOHC, William Boardman Materials, 1966; 3.0 items (Box 18)
  - EOHC, Richard C. Henry Materials, 1966-1975; 63.0 items (Box 18)
  - EOHC, Robert Meier Materials, 1966-1968; 19.0 items (Box 18)
  - EOHC, Seth Shulman Material, 1969-1971; 30.0 items (Box 18)
  - EOHC, Thomas Winter, Jr. Materials, 1956-1967; 34.0 items (Box 18)
  - EOHC, William A. Sloan Material, 1964-1966; 30.0 items (Box 18)
  - EOHC, XLA February 27, 1986, 1.0 item (Box 18)
  - The E.O. Hulbert Center for Space Research, undated; 2.0 items; Friedman, Herbert, 1916-2000 (Box 19)
  - George Carruthers Materials, NRL, 1970-1971; 28.0 items (Box 19)
  - George Carruthers Materials, NRL, 1972; 8.0 items (Box 19)
  - George Carruthers Materials, NRL, 1973; 18.0 items (Box 19)
    This is folder 1 of 2.
  - George Carruthers Materials, NRL, 1973; 10.0 items (Box 19)
    This is folder 2 of 2.
  - George Carruthers Materials, NRL, 1974; 6.0 items (Box 19)
  - George Carruthers Materials, NRL, 1975-1977; 7.0 items (Box 19)
  - George Carruthers Materials, NRL, Flemming Award, 1969-1971; 29.0 items (Box 19)
  - George Carruthers Materials, NRL, S-201 Apollo Lunar Surface Camera, 1969-1974; 50.0 items (Box 19)
  - HEAO, 0.1-20 MeV Gamma Ray Laboratory, 1970; 5.0 items (Box 20)
  - HEAO-A, undated; 1.0 item; Friedman, Herbert, 1916-2000 (Box 20)
  - HEAO Articles, 1977-1978; 24.0 items (Box 20)
  - HEAO Correspondence, 1970; 26.0 items (Box 20)
  - HEAO Correspondence, 1971; 26.0 items (Box 20)
  - HEAO Correspondence, 1972; 19.0 items (Box 20)
  - HEAO Correspondence, 1973; 29.0 items (Box 20)
  - HEAO Correspondence, 1974; 23.0 items (Box 20)
  - HEAO Correspondence, 1975; 55.0 items (Box 20)
  - HEAO Correspondence, 1976; 67.0 items (Box 20)
  - HEAO Correspondence, 1977; 56.0 items (Box 21)
  - HEAO Correspondence, 1978-1979; 55.0 items (Box 21)
  - HEAO Guest Observation Program, 1977-1980; 40.0 items (Box 21)
  - HEAO Management and Technical Proposal, The Phase C/D Program, Large Area, X-Ray Survey Experiment (LAXRAY) - AXR - 3, 1971; 2.0 items (Box 21)
  - HEAO Program Draft, 1974; 1.0 item (Box 21)
  - HEAO, A Proposal to Fly Large Area X-Ray Counters and Associated Hardware Aboard the HEAO, 1970; 3.0 items (Box 22)
  - HEAO I Annual Report 1978, 1.0 item (Box 22)
  - HEAO-1 Mission Evaluation Final Report, 20 April 1979; 1.0 item (Box 22)
  - Hulburt, Edward O., Remarks on EOHC Groundbreaking, 1965; 1.0 item (Box 22)
  - Identification of Radioactivity in Special Samples, 1949; 1.0 item (Box 22)
  - Indian Satellite Program, NRL, 1971; 6.0 items (Box 22)
  - Instruction Manual for Special Equipment, Project 31N03-08, undated; 1.0 item (Box 22)
  - Instructions for Operation of RFL Type Ground Station, undated; 2.0 items (Box 22)
  - Instructions for Operation of TR Type Ground Station (Partial), undated; 3.0 items (Box 22)
  - Interscience Publishers Inc., 1956; 4.0 items (Box 22)
  - Miscellaneous, 1988; 1.0 item (Box 22)
  - Miscellaneous Abstracts, 1958; undated; 35.0 items (Box 22)
  - NRL 75 - Outline, undated; 1.0 item (Box 22)
  - NRL Labstracts, 1966-1968; 3.0 items (Box 22)
  - NRL Retirement Announcement, 26 February 1980; 1.0 item (Box 22)
  - NRL, NRL Space Science Program Background Information, 1974; 1.0 item (Box 22)
  - NRL, NRL Stratospheric Research, 1975; 1.0 item (Box 22)
  - NRL, Operation Sandstone Nuclear Explosions, 1948; 1.0 item (Box 22)
  - NRL, Optics Division, Coloration of Crystals By X-Rays and Nuclear Radiation, 1947; 2.0 items (Box 22)
  - NRL, Optics Division, Crystal Dosimeters, 1950; 1953; 4.0 items (Box 22)
  - NRL, Optics Division, Low Voltage Self-Quenching Geiger Counters, 1947; 3.0 items (Box 22)
  - NRL, Optics Division, Problem Number 37P07-04, 1951-1953; 10.0 items (Box 22)
  - NRL, Optics Division, Problem Number 73H02-01, 1955; 3.0 items (Box 22)
  - NRL, Optics Division, Problem Number 73P07-04, 1954; 9.0 items (Box 22)
  - NRL, Optics Division, Problem Number 37P07-04R, 1949-1950; 17.0 items (Box 22)
  - NRL, Optics Division, Problem Number 37P08-01R, 1949; 2.0 items (Box 23)
  - NRL, Optics Division, Problem Number H02-01, 1954-1958; 13.0 items (Box 23)
  - NRL, Optics Division, Problem Numbers S-1696, 1772, 1956; 2.0 items (Box 23)
  - NRL, A Proposal for a 3-Axis Stabilized X-Ray Observatory, 1976; 1.0 item (Box 23)
  - Photo Reproduction Receipts, 1995; 11.0 items (Box 23)
  - Recovery and ID of Atomic Bomb Fission Products, 1955; 1.0 item (Box 23)
  - Report, 1957 Report to Committee on Cosmic-Terrestrial Relationships, 3.0 items (Box 23)
  - Report, Astrophysical Measurements from Rockets, 1958; 1.0 item (Box 23)
  - Report, Astronomical Observations in the Far Ultraviolet, 1958; 2.0 items (Box 23)
  - Report, Far Ultraviolet Radiation in the Night Sky, 1958; 1.0 item (Box 23)
  - Report, Fluorescence Analysis, 1957; 1.0 item (Box 23)
  - Report, IGY Upper Air Research with Rockets and Satellites, 1958; 1.0 items (Box 23)
  - Report, Intensity of Solar Lyman Alpha and Adjacent Ultraviolet Emission Lines, 1958; 1.0 item (Box 23)
  - Report, The Ionospheric F2 Region, undated; 1.0 item (Box 23)
  - Report, A Lyman Alpha Experiment for the Vanguard Satellite, 1956; 1.0 item (Box 23)
  - Report, Molecular Oxygen Densities in the Mesosphere at Fort Churchill, 1.0 item (Box 23)
  - Report, Observational Astrophysics from Rockets I. Nebular Photometry at 1300A, undated; 1.0 item (Box 23)
  - Report, Observations of the Intensity of Solar Lyman Alpha Emissions, undated; 1.0 item (Box 23)
  - Report, Optical Aspect System for Rockets, 1956; 2.0 items (Box 23)
    Seven photos from this folder removed to Series XI.
  - Report, Photoelectric Measurements of Solar X-Rays and Ultraviolet Radiation, undated; 1.0 item (Box 23)
  - Report, Rocket Astronomy, 1958; 1.0 item (Box 23)
  - Report, Rocket Astronomy in the Far Ultraviolet, 1958; 1.0 item (Box 23)
  - Report, Rocket Observation of X-Ray Emission in a Solar Flare, undated; 1.0 item (Box 23)
  - Report, Russian Satellite Instrumentation, 1957; 1.0 item (Box 23)
  - Report, A Satellite Experiment to Determine the Distribution of Hydrogen in Space, 1956; 1.0 item (Box 23)
  - Report, Satellite Instrumentation, 1957; 1.0 item (Box 23)
  - Report, Scientific Experiments in IGY Satellites, 1957; 1.0 item (Box 23)
    Four items have been removed to Series XI, Photographs.
  - Report, Scientific Instrumentation in IGY Satellites, 1956; 2.0 items (Box 23)
  - Report, Solar Flare Program and Ionizing Radiation in the Night Sky, 1958; 1.0 item (Box 23)
  - Report, Solar X-Ray Emission and The Height of D-Layer During Radio Fadeout, undated; 1.0 item (Box 23)
  - Report, Solar X-Ray Emissions, undated; 1.0 item (Box 23)
  - Report, The Solar X-Ray Spectrum and the Density of the Upper Atmosphere, 1956; undated; 1.0 item (Box 23)
  - Report, The Use of Radiation Absorption and Luminescence in Upper Air Density Measurements, 1955; 1.0 item (Box 23)
  - Report, X-Ray and Ultraviolet Emission of Sikar Flares - IGY Project 10.3, 1957 (Box 23)
  - Report, X-Ray Emission of Solar Flares, 1958; 1.0 item (Box 23)
  - Research Appointment, Blank Appointment, 1963; 1.0 item (Box 23)
  - Roger L. Easton Award for Engineering Excellence, Establishing Documents, 1964-1997; 25.0 items (Box 23)
  - Sadeh, Dror, Search for X-Ray Pulsars Using HEAO A1 Data, 19 August 1976; 1.0 item (Box 23)
  - NRL, Space Highlights, 1968-1978; 9.0 items (Box 23)
  - NRL, The Solar Radiation Monitoring Program and Progress in Identification of Empirical Communication Forecasting Criteria, 1968; 1.0 item (Box 23)
  - Special Filter Paper Analyses and Preliminary Information Derived Therefrom, 1949; 1.0 item (Box 23)
  - Sponsors' Day Lecture, 1958; 2.0 items (Box 23)
  - Ten Year Research Plan for the Space Science Division, 1975; 3.0 items (Box 23)
  - Wing, Albert, 1951; 24.0 items (Box 23)
  - Unidentified, "A Key to Solar Influence in Atmospheric Warming... ", undated; 1.0 item (Box 23)
  - Unidentified, Upper Atmospher Research, undated; 1.0 item (Box 23)
- Series V. Patents, 0.5 linear feet
  Series V is made up of materials regarding the patents applied for, and awarded to Dr. Friedman during his time at the Navy Research Laboratory. In his lifetime Dr. Friedman was awarded 50 patents, all of which are reflected here in some manner.
  - Advanced Metals Research Corporation, Correspondence, 1957-1963; 23.0 items (Box 24)
  - Advanced Metals Research Corporation, Miscellaneous, 1959-1960; 5.0 items (Box 24)
  - Co-Glow Radiation Detecter, Correspondence, Reports, Incidents, 1955-1961; undated; 43.0 items (Box 24)
  - Co-Glow Radiation Detector, Notes and Drawings, undated; 20.0 items (Box 20)
  - Design Drawings, undated; 4.0 items (Box 24)
  - Flame and Fire Detector, 1947; 1959; 19.0 items (Box 24)
  - Flicker Fusion Test Apparatus, 1944; 6.0 items (Box 24)
  - Gas Detection, 1954; 2.0 items (Box 24)
  - Geiger-Mueller Photon Counters, 1952; undated; 5.0 items (Box 24)
  - Ice Detector, 1945; 3.0 items (Box 24)
  - John Wiley and Sons, Inc., 1974-1977; 3.0 items (Box 24)
  - Legal Documents, 1946; 1949; 1955; 3.0 items (Box 24)
  - North American Philips Co., 1948-1960; 52.0 items (Box 24)
  - Patent Correspondence, 1947-1965; 59.0 items (Box 24)
  - Patent Interference, Case 84, 823, 1949-1951; 6.0 items (Box 24)
  - Patent Records, 1950; 1967; 2000; undated.; 13.0 items (Box 24)
  - Patents Assigned to H. Friedman, undated; 1.0 item (Box 24)
  - Philips Electronic Instruments, 1951; 1961-1962; 1965; 9.0 items (Box 24)
  - Teflon Coated Photon Counter Tube, 1964; 1966; 5.0 items (Box 24)
  - Ultra-Violet Gas Analysis, 1959-1960; 9.0 items (Box 24)
- Series VI. Works by Others, 1.5 linear feet
  Series VI contains works by others, including some his co-workers at the Navy Research Laboratory. Prominently featured are the works of Talbot A. Chubb, George R. Carruthers, Irving Blifford and Riccardo Giacconi, co-recipient of the 2002 Nobel Prize for Physics.
  - Polarization Measurements Using the Bragg Crystal Spectrometers on Hinotori, 1983; 1.0 item; Akita, Kyo (Box 25)
  - An Interview with Dr. Edward Olson Hulburt, 1977; 1.0 item; Allison, David Kite (Box 25)
  - Space Age, Forward, undated; 1.0 item; Andorfer, Gregory (Box 25)
  - Archibald Garrod and the Birth of an Idea, 1976; 1.0 item; Bearn, Alexander G., 1923-2009 (Box 25)
    Garrod, A. H. (Alfred Henry), 1846-1879
  - Yohkoh Reveals Site of Solar Flare Energy Release, 1995; 1.0 item; Benka, Stephen G. (Box 25)
  - New Vies of Neutron Stars, 1999 February; 1.0 item; Bildsten, Lars; Strohmayer, Tod (Box 25)
  - Untitled Manuscript, 1992; 1.0 item; Bing, George F., 1924-; May, Michael M., 1925- (Box 25)
  - Balloon Observation of the Isotropic Component of Celestical X-Rays Up to 90 keV, 1966 March 15; 1.0 item; Bleeker, J. A. M. (Box 25)
  - Commentary on Ziegler's Book and Other Information Concerning Long-Range Detection of Atomic Explosions, undated; 1.0 item; Blifford, Irving (Box 25)
  - Filtration of Radioactivity in the Air, 1995; 1.0 item; Blifford, Irving (Box 25)
  - Methods of Sampling Atmospheric Radioactivity, undated; 1.0 item; Blifford, Irving (Box 25)
  - NRL Detection of the First Russian Atomic Bomb, 1992 July; 1.0 item; Blifford, Irving (Box 25)
  - The Oppenheimer Hearing Revisited, 1992 December; 1.0 item; Blifford, Irving (Box 25)
  - The Scientific Big-Time, 1994 December; 1.0 item; Blifford, Irving (Box 25)
  - The Lifetime of Dust in the Atmosphere, 1994 December; 1.0 item; Blifford, Irving (Box 25)
  - Detecting Gravitational Waves, 1980; 1.0 item; Boughn, Stephen (Box 25)
  - Eclipse Rocket History, undated; 1.0 item; Brueckner, G. E. (Guenter E.) (Box 25)
  - Atomic and Molecular Hydrogen in Interstellar Space, 1969; 1.0 item; Carruthers, George R. (Box 25)
  - Far Ultra-Violet Photometry of Orion Stars, 1969; 1.0 item; Carruthers, George R. (Box 25)
  - Further Developments of Magnetically-Focused, Internal Optic Image Converters, 1971; 1.0 item; Carruthers, George R. (Box 25)
  - Far Ultraviolet Wide Field Imaging and Photometry: Spartan-202 Mark II Far Ultraviolet Camera, 1988; 1.0 item; Carruthers, George R. (Box 25)
  - The Invisible Mass Budget of the Galaxy, 1967; 1.0 item; Carruthers, George R. (Box 25)
  - Molecular Hyrdrogen Detected in Interstellar Space, 1970; 1.0 item; Carruthers, George R. (Box 25)
  - Our Knowledge of the Solar System, 1973; 2.0 items; Carruthers, George R. (Box 25)
  - Rocket Observation of Interstellar Molecular Hydrogen, 1970; 1.0 item; Carruthers, George R. (Box 25)
  - The Spartan-281 Far Ultraviolet Imaging Spectrograph, 1988; 1.0 item; Carruthers, George R. (Box 25)
  - Development of General Relativity, 1974 November 1; 1.0 item; Chandrasekhar, S. (Subrahmanyan), 1910-1995 (Box 25)
  - Making It Happen, 1995; 1.0 item; Christman, Albert B. (Box 25)
  - Cold Fusion as an Interaction Between Ion Band States, 1991; 3.0 items; Chubb, Talbot A. (Talbot Albert) (Box 25)
  - The Study of Planetary Atmospheres By Atmospheric Fluorescence, 1968; 1.0 item; Donahue, Thomas M. (Box 25)
  - Recent Advances in EUV Solar Astronomy, 1996; 1.0 item; Doschek, G. A. (Box 25)
  - Rocket Measurements of Low Energy Electrons and Optical Emissions in the Dayglow and Aurora, 1971; 1.0 item; Feldman, Paul D. (Box 25)
  - Solar Spectroscopy in the Far UV Through X-Ray Wavelngth Regions: Status and Prospects, 1988; 1.0 item; Feldman, U. (Box 25)
  - Global Climate Change Challenge, 1992; 1.0 item; Ferneau, Mark.; South, David. (Box 25)
  - The New Gamma-Ray Astronomy, 1998; 1.0 item; Gehrels, Neil; Paul, Jacques, 1943- (Box 25)
  - A Proposal For an Institute for X-Ray Astronomy, 1974-1975; 17.0 items; Giacconi, Riccardo (Box 25)
  - Mars: A Generation of Discoveries, undated; 1.0 item; Goody, Richard M. (Box 25)
  - The First Decade of X-Ray Astronomy - A Personal View, 1993; 1.0 item; Gursky, Herbert (Box 25)
  - Detection of Signals Far Below the Photon Noise Limit, 1960 January 25; 1.0 item; Harwit, Martin, 1931- (Box 26)
  - Energy Spectrum of Galactic X-Rays, 1966 May; 1.0 item; Hayakawa, Sachio, 1923- (Box 26)
  - Absorption of Crab Nebula Rays, 1972; 1.0 item; Friedman, Herbert, 1916-2000; Henry, Richard B. C. (Box 26)
  - Excess Background Radiation of Soft X-Rays at the Galactic Pole and Plane, 1971; 1.0 item; Henry, Richard B. C. (Box 26)
  - Atomic Shield 1974/1952, Chapter 12, 1947; 1952; 1.0 item; Duncan, Francis; Hewlett, Richard G. (Box 26)
  - The Resurgence of Research By Sounding Rockets, undated; 1.0 item; Hines, C. O. (Colin O.) (Box 26)
  - Universal Truths, 1990 October; 1.0 item; Horgan, John, 1953- (Box 26)
  - Space and Science, 1992; undated; 3.0 items; Hoyle, Fred, Sir (Box 26)
  - Remote Sensing of Environment, Outlook from 1976, 1.0 item; Huh, Oscar K. (Oscar Karl), 1935- (Box 26)
  - Chapter 5 - Solar Particle Radiation... (Partial), 1954; 1.0 item; Hulburt, Edward O. (Edward Olson), 1890- (Box 26)
  - On Writing a Scientific Paper, 1947; 1.0 item; Hulburt, Edward O. (Edward Olson), 1890- (Box 26)
  - The Temperature of the Lower Atmosphere of the Earth, 1931 November 15; 1.0 item; Hulburt, Edward O. (Edward Olson), 1890- (Box 26)
  - Space Telescopes on a Budget, undated; 1.0 item; Hunten, Donald M.; Rose, Leonard J. (Box 26)
  - Can SSTs Affect Ozone and Skin Cancer?, 1973; 1.0 item; Johnson, Francis S. (Box 26)
  - Michelson Interferometry - Fifty Years Later, undated; 1.0 item; Johnston, K. J. (Kenneth J.), 1941-; Mozurkewich, David (Box 26)
  - IMAPS: A High Resolution Echelle Spectrogram to Record Far-Ultraviolet Spectra of Stars from Sounding Rockets, 1988; 1.0 item; Jenkins, Edward B. (Box 26)
  - Long Baseline Optical Interferometry, undated; 1.0 item; Johnston, K. J. (Kenneth J.), 1941- (Box 26)
  - The Case "Thalofide Cell:" Its Use in Spectroscopy, 1927 March; 1.0 item; Kaplan, Joseph A., 1902-1991 (Box 26)
  - The Galactic Center: A Wide-Field, Low Frequency Image, 1999 January 27; 1.0 item; Kassim, Namir E. (Namir El-Sheick), 1958- (Box 26)
  - Sun-Weather Relationships, undated; 1.0 item; King, J. W. (Joseph William) (Box 26)
  - On Line Polarization Measurements in the Solar Flare Spectra Obtained Aboard the "Intercosmos-4" Satellite, 1981; 1.0 item; Krutov, V. V. (Box 26)
  - Atmospheric Radioactivity Studies at the U.S. Naval Research Laboratory, 1959; 1.0 item; Lockhart, L. B., Jr. (Box 26)
  - The International Space Year (ISY) and the International Geosphere-biosphere Program (IGBP), undated; 1.0 item; Malone, Thomas F. (Box 26)
  - Strange Xenon, Extinct Superheavy Elements, and the Solar Neutrino Puzzle, 1977; 1.0 item; Manuel, O. (Oliver), 1936- (Box 26)
  - Modern Poetry and Astronomy, 1983 March-April; 1.0 item; Marschall, Laurence A. (Box 26)
  - Vanguard, A History: NASA SP-4202, 1998; 1.0 item; Green, Constance McLaughlin, 1897-1975; Lomask, Milton (Box 26)
  - Gamma-Ray Burst Overview, 1998; 1.0 item; Meegan, Charles A., 1944- (Box 26)
  - Remarks on the Origin of the Cosmic Radiation, 1990; 1.0 item; Meyer, P. (Peter) (Box 26)
  - The Keck Telescope, 1989 March-April; 1.0 item; Nelson, Jerry (Box 26)
  - Humanity or Robotics in Space, 1990 April 26; 1.0 item; Oda, Minoru, 1923- (Box 26)
  - Evolution of the Unsolved Problems, 1990 April 27; 1.0 item; Oda, Minoru, 1923- (Box 26)
  - Optical Space Astronomy, undated; 1.0 item; O’Dell, C. Robert (Charles Robert), 1937 (Box 26)